John A. Holmes Papers MS007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Poetry, 1922 -- 1962; 1940 -- 1961; MS007.001; 7.25 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s)
  - The saving grace, 1949-12-01; MS007.001.003.00531; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 091. Revision in 9:063 is dated October 1949. Revision in 9:063 is titled: No sign. Published in The double root, p. 72; Tufts Alumni Review, 4:3, Winter 1950, and the New York Times Book Review, January 21, 1951. Printed on Christmas card for 1949. revision in 9:063
  - Seasonal wisdom, 1932-02-01; MS007.001.003.00532; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 092. Published in Address to the living, p. 42; Sewanee Review, 45:378-79, July 1937; Tuftonian n s, 11:66, April 1937; Virginia Quarterly Review, 9:553, October 1933. revisions in 3:93; 10:010, p. 26; and 10:034, p. 28
  - The secret, 1932-02-01; MS007.001.003.00533; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 095. Annotated by Unknown Published in Voices, 74:9, February-March 1934. duplicates in 3:95 and 10:034, p. 80, revisions in 4:23; 10:010, p. 27; 10:034, p. 29; 10:035, p. 130
  - Self portrait, 1948-08-14; MS007.001.003.00534; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 096. Annotated: "Chautauqua" Published in The double root, p. 31.
  - Send, send, 1947-04-01; MS007.001.003.00535; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 097. revision in 5:074 is annotated Published in Tuftonian, 6:87, January 1948. revisions in April 1947, 5:074 and 10:033, p. 26
  - Silence, 1946-02-01; MS007.001.003.00536; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 098. Revision in 6:071 is dated February 1946. Published in The symbols, p. 38; Poetry, 68:261, August 1946. revisions in 3:99; 6:071; 10:033, p. 25; and 10:035, p.54
  - Since you asked, MS007.001.003.00537; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 100. revision in 10:033, p. 17
  - The skin of your face, 1950-03-01; MS007.001.003.00538; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 101. Annotated. Revision in 10:035, p. 52 has minor annotations. Published in The symbols, p. 36. duplicate in March 1950, 3:101 and revision in 10:035, p. 52
  - Sleep and poetry, 1933-01-01; MS007.001.003.00539; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 102. Published in Voices, 74:8, February-March 1934. revisions in 4:23; 10:010, p. 34; 10:034, p. 50; 10:035, p. 135
  - Sonnet for solace [O heart be quick], MS007.001.003.00540; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 104. Published in American Poetry Journal, p. 7, February 1934. Revision in 6:056 is titled "O heart be quick" and annotated: "written when I was in college, for and about a classmate whose fiancee died a month after their graduation." revisions in 4:53; 6:056; 10:010, p. 33; 10:034, p. 11; 10:035, p. 135
  - To the queen's men [Sonnet to the queen's men], 1933-06-01; MS007.001.003.00541; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 105. Published in Address to the Living, p. 68; Saturday Review of Literature, 10:377, December 30, 1933. duplicate, entitled [Sonnet to the queen's men] in 3:105 and revisions in revision, June 1933, 4:56; 7:014; 10:010, p. 35; 10:034, p. 61
  - Spring is the peace, 1946-01-01; MS007.001.003.00542; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 106. Revision in 6:077 is dated January 1946. Published in The symbols, p. 28; Atlantic, 177:83, June 1946. revisions in 3:107; 6:077; and 10:033, p. 10, duplicate in 10:035, p. 47
  - Summer morning porch, 1954-07-28; MS007.001.003.00543; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 108. Annotated: "Chautauqua Lake" Published in Hopkins Review, 2:48, Spring 1949; New York Herald-Tribune, July 28 1954. revisions in 6:078 and 6:079, duplicate in 10:036, p. 55
  - Summer opera, MS007.001.003.00544; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 109. Annotated Published in The symbols, p. 14. duplicate in 10:035, p. 34
  - September valentine, 1946-09-01; MS007.001.003.00545; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 110. Duplicate in 3:110 is titled: Last look around. Duplicate in 3:110 is dated September 1946. Published in The symbols, p. 32; Literature: An Introduction (New York: McGraw-Hill, 1960) p. 322. duplicates in September 1946, 3:110; 10:033, p. 41; 10:035, p. 50
  - Better than all [Better than all these], MS007.001.003.00546; Holmes, John (Box 3)
    Box 3 folder 111. Published in The fortune teller, p. 97; The symbols, p. 42; University of Kansas City Review, 20:57, Autumn 1953. revisions in 9:075; 10:035, p. 58; 11:003, p. 77
  - Take home this heart, 1933-02-01; MS007.001.004.00547; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 001. Published in Address to the living, p. 21; Sewanee Review, 42:356-57, July 1934. revisions in 4:54; 7:014; 10:010, p. 49; 10:034, p. 58
  - Then the sun came out, MS007.001.004.00548; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 002. Published in Map of my country, p. 46. Printed on Christmas card for 1943. revision in 10:035, p. 165
  - The new art, 1953-10-01; MS007.001.004.00549; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 116. Includes copy with revision. Duplicate in 4:116 annotated. Revision 5:44 annotated. Published in Liberal Context, 1:11, Winter 1961. duplicate in 4:116, revisions in 5:43; 5:44; 10:035, p. 23
  - Then he will sleep, 1932; MS007.001.004.00550; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 004. Published in Address to the living, p. 25; Harper, 165:20, June 1932; New York Herald-Tribune, May 29 1932. revisions in 6:007; 7:014; 10:034, p. 20; 10:034, p. 117; 10:038, p. 3, duplicate in 10:010, p. 22
  - Till music cries again, 1932-02-01; MS007.001.004.00551; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 005. Published in Address to the living, p. 24; Saturday Review of Literature, 9:662, June 24, 1933; Boston Herald, October 20 1935. revisions in 4:6; 7:014; 10:010, p. 41; 10:038, p. 8, duplicate in 10:034, p. 38
  - To keep and not to keep [These conditions] [What to keep, what to lose], 1936-12-01; MS007.001.004.00552; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 007. Revision in 9:004 is titled: "What to keep, what to lose"; revision in 8:016 titled "These conditions". Published in Map of my country, p. 40; Poetry, 56:246, August 1941. revisions in 6:048; 6:087; 6:088; 6:089; 6:090; 7:008; 9:004; December 1936, 8:016; 10:010, p. 127; 11:002, p. 42
  - To live in, 1945-12-01; MS007.001.004.00553; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 008. Revision in 6:039 is annotated: "This is one way of thinking about Atkins Place, on Medford Hillside, where I live." Published in The double root, p. 11; Atlantic, 178:93, September 1946. Printed on Christmas card for 1945. revisions in 6:039 and 10:033, p. 1
  - The tower stands, MS007.001.004.00554; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 010. Published in Eleusis of Chi Omego, 55:209-10, May 1953.
  - To my sisters and my brother [To my teacher], 1933-04-01; MS007.001.004.00555; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 011. Annotated Published in Address to the living, p. 70; Published as "To my sisters and brother" in Harper, 167:313, August 1933. revisions in 10:010, p. 46; 10:034, p. 54; 4:012, duplicate in 10:034, p. 110
  - Truth about pictures, 1958-06-20; MS007.001.004.00556; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 013. Annotated. Revision in 5:86 dated June 19, 1958. Revision in 10:037, p. 125 is annotated. Published in Massachusetts Review, 1:576, May 1960. revisions in June 19, 1958, 5:86; 6:096; 10:037, p. 125
  - Two and a little house, MS007.001.004.00557; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 014.
  - The unforgiven, 1958-03-02; MS007.001.004.00558; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 015. Published in Unitarian Register, 138:11, October 1959. revision in 6:100 and duplicate in 10:037, p. 143
  - Unlikely tale, MS007.001.004.00559; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 016. Published in Poetry, 47:79, November 1935; Step Ladder, 22:24, January 1936. revisions in 3:17; 4:23; 10:010, p. 56; 10:035, p. 139, duplicate in 10:034, p. 142
  - Unpublished preface to a Ph.D. thesis, MS007.001.004.00560; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 018. Published in Map of my country, p. 62; Atlantic, 166:772, December 1940; B.C. Teacher, 20:332, March 1941. revisions in 6:101 and 11:002, p. 61
  - Ten-thirty class, 1941; MS007.001.004.00561; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 018. Revision in 6:066 is annotated: "This is the other side of the picture from "Teaching Program." Sometimes professors lecture when the heart is breaking." Published in Map of my country, p. 64; Tuftonian, 1:16, January 1941. revisions in 5:45; 6:066; 11:002, p. 63, sound recording in 64:001
  - The valiant, MS007.001.004.00562; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 019. Published in American Scholar, 5:215, March 1936; New York Herald-Tribune, May 17 1936. revisions in 10:010, p. 112 and 10:035, p. 155
  - Very young, very old, 1955-10-14; MS007.001.004.00563; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 020. Annotated: "for Frances and Evan". Revision in 9:111 is handwritten. Duplicate in 10:026 is titled: Very young, very old. Published in Lyric, 36:75, Fall 1956. revisions in 9:111 and 10:037, p. 69, duplicate in 10:026
  - The voice, 1932; MS007.001.004.00564; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 021. Revision in 4:22 is annotated Published in American Poetry Journal, p. 17, October 1934. [Summer 1932] revisions in 4:22; 4:23; 10:010, p. 39; 10:034, p. 35; 10:034, p. 113; 10:035, p. 136, duplicate, Summer 1932, 4:21
  - Poem for my 27th year [For the poet's birthday], MS007.001.004.00565; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 025. Revision in 6:009 is titled: Twelfth- Night Dream. Revision in 7:028 is titled: Twelfth Night Dream. Revision and duplicate in 7:045 is titled: For a birthday poem. Revision in 7:073 is titled Twenty-Seventh Birthday Poem. Revision in 10:034, p. 123 is titled: Twelfth night dream. Published as "For the poet's birthday" in Address to the living, p. 16; Voices, 74:9-10, February-March 1934. duplicates in 4:25; 7:045; 10:010, p. 18, revisions in 6:009; 7:028; 7:045; 7:073; 10:034, p. 19; 10:034, p. 123
  - All except Mary Ann, MS007.001.004.00566; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 026. Published in Ladies' Home Journal, 56:52, May 1939. duplicates in 10:010, p. 19; 10:034, p. 21; 10:035, p. 128
  - The way the stars went up, 1935; MS007.001.004.00567; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 028. Revision in 10:011 is dated 1935. Published in Voices, 80:5-6, February-March 1935; New York Herald-Tribune, February 10 1935, p. II8. http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/7SG3JLN revisions in 1935, 10:011; 10:010, p. 82; 10:035, p. 145; 10:038, p. 23
  - Weather making, 1954; MS007.001.004.00568; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 030. Published in Harper, 210:67, May 1955. duplicates in 10:035, p. 1; 10:036, p. 58; 10:037, p. 1, sound recording in 64:001
  - What the books do, 1954; MS007.001.004.00569; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 031. Contains a second copy embellished with calligraphy. Published in Saturday Review of Literature, 15:16, November 7, 1936. revisions in 6:055; 10:010, p. 99 and duplicate in 10:035, p. 153
  - Who are they?, 1944-12-01; MS007.001.004.00570; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 032. Annotated. Revision in 8:087 is dated December 1944. Revision in 8:087 is titled How are they treating you? Published in Tuftonian 6, no 1:45, 1947; University of Kansas City Review, 13:43, Autumn 1946. revisions in December 1944, 8:087; 10:033, p. 36; 10:035, p. 95-96; 10:037, p. 45
  - A willing suspension, 1960-01-01; MS007.001.004.00571; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 033. Duplicate in 5:100 dated 1961 Published in The fortune teller, p. 103; Saturday Review, 43:28, December 31, 1960; Tuftonian, 16:29-30, May 1960. Printed on Christmas card for 1960. duplicate in 4:33 and in 1961, 5:100, revisions in 10:037, p. 148; 11:003, p. 82. sound recording in 67:001
  - Without honor, MS007.001.004.00572; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 034. Published in Fair warning, p. 34 revisions in 4:35; 10:010, p. 58; 10:034, p. 70
  - The wreath, 1951; MS007.001.004.00573; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 036. Revision in 10:035, p. 109 is annotated. Published in Yankee, 20:51, December 1956; Medford, Massachusetts Daily Mercury, December 21 1956. Printed on Christmas card for 1951. revision in 10:035, p. 109 and duplicate in 10:037, p. 25
  - Hello, MS007.001.004.00574; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 038. Revision in 10:035, p. 100 is annotated. revisions in 8:085; 10:035, p. 100; 10:037, p. 66
  - Underwater, MS007.001.004.00575; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 039. Revision in 4:40 is annotated. Published in American Poetry Journal, p. 33, June 1934. revision in 4:40, duplicates in 10:010, p. 21; 10:034, p. 24; 10:035, p. 129
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.004.00576; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 041.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.004.00577; Holmes, John (Box 4)
  - Sally [Warning with love], MS007.001.004.00578; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 043. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revisions in 7:014 & 10:010 are titled "Warning with love". Published as "Warning with love" in Address to the living, p. 95.
  - One place, MS007.001.004.00579; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 043. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" Published in Voices, 87:4, Autumn 1936. revisions in 10:010, p. 90 and 10:035, p. 147, duplicate in 10:034, p. 126
  - These ghosts, MS007.001.004.00580; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 043. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revision in 10:010. p. 91 & 10:035, p. 148 is titled: "These hands, these ghosts" Published in Voices, 87:4, Autumn 1936. revisions in 10:010, p. 91; 10:035, p. 148; 10:038, p. 16, duplicate in 10:034, p. 126
  - Mellow and merry, MS007.001.004.00581; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 044. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" duplicates in 10:010, p. 91 and 10:034, p. 127, revision in 10:035, p. 148
  - Living in cities, MS007.001.004.00582; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 044. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" Published in Fair warning, p. 35; Boston Herald, April 15 1936; New York Times, September 4 1938; Tufts Weekly, April 16 1936. revision in 10:010, p. 92 and duplicate in 10:034, p. 127
  - Various loyalties, MS007.001.004.00583; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 044. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revision in 10:010 is annotated. revisions in 8:103; 10:010, p. 92; 10:035, p. 149, duplicate in 10:034, p. 127
  - Arrows and angry snakes, MS007.001.004.00584; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 045. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" Published in Address to the living, p. 98. revisions in 7:014 and 10:010, p. 93, duplicate in 10:034, p. 128
  - Old Adam in us, MS007.001.004.00585; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 045. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revision in 10:010 is annotated. Published in Address to the living, p. 93. revisions in 7:014 and 10:010, p. 93, duplicate in 10:034, p. 128
  - After two years, MS007.001.004.00586; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 045. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" Published in Address to the living, p. 19.; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1936 and Yearbook of American Poetry, (New York: Poetry Digest Association, 1937), p. 79; Voices, 87:3, Autumn 1936; New York Sun, April 3 1937; Niagara Falls Gazette, December 5 1936. revisions in 7:014 and 10:010, p. 94, duplicate in 10:034, p. 128
  - King time, MS007.001.004.00587; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 046. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revision in 10:010 is annotated. revisions in 10:010, p. 94 and 10:035, p. 149, duplicate in 10:034, p. 129
  - The secret epilogue [Epilogue untold], MS007.001.004.00588; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 046. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revision in 10:010, p. 95 & 10:035, p. 150 is titled: "Epilogue untold" Published as "Epilogue untold" in Anthology Verse for 1936 and Yearbook of American Poetry, (New York: Poetry Digest Assoiciation, 1937), p. 77; Voices, 87:5, Autumn 1936. revisions in 10:010, p. 95; 10:035, p. 150; 10:023, duplicate in 10:034, p. 129
  - That is the way you look [Face to face], MS007.001.004.00589; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 046. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revision in 10:010 is titled: "Face to face" Published as "Face to face" in Fair warning, p. 39 revision in 10:010, p. 95, duplicate in 10:034, p. 129
  - Legend and truth, MS007.001.004.00590; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 047. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" Published in Address to the living, p. 64.; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1936, (New York: Poetry Digest Association, 1936), p. 73; Atlantic, 155:604, May 1935; Farm Bureau Exchange, 21:4, January 1936; Fiction Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 5:44, May 1937; Literary Digest, 119:31, May 11, 1935; Yankee, 9:1, July 1945; Boston Globe, May 14 1935; New York Herald-Tribune, April 28 1935. revisions in 7:014; 10:017; 10:010, p. 96; 10:038, p. 16, duplicate in 10:034, p. 130
  - From everlasting unto everlasting, MS007.001.004.00591; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 047. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" duplicate in 10:034, p. 130
  - If I were old [The bitter thought], MS007.001.004.00592; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 047. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" Published in Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1936 and Yearbook of American Poetry, (New York: Poetry Digest Association, 1937), p. 78; Voices, 87:5, Autumn 1936. revisions in 10:010, p. 97; 10:035, p. 151; 10:023, duplicate in 10:034, p. 130
  - The mind by day, MS007.001.004.00593; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 048. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revision in 10:010 is crossed out. Published in New Yorker, 13:32, November 20, 1937; Providence, Rhode Island Journal, November 28 1937; Waterbury, Connecticut American, November 24 1937. revisions in 6:059; 10:010, p. 98; 10:010, p. 136; 10:035, p. 152; 10:038, p. 25, duplicate in 10:034, p. 131
  - Poets take heart, MS007.001.004.00594; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 048. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" Published in New York Herald-Tribune, January 21 1955. revisions in 10:010, p. 97 and 10:035, p. 151, duplicate in 10:034, p. 131
  - You living look [A hundred years from now], MS007.001.004.00595; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 048. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes" Published in Address to the living, p. 12; Poems Editors Buy (Pasadena, CA: Star-News Publishing Co., 1939) p. 19; Atlantic, 158:348, September 1936; Fiction Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 5:44, May 1937; New York Herald-Tribune, August 15 1936. Revisions in 10:034, p. 75; 10:017; 10:010, p. 76, duplicate in 10:034, p. 131
  - Two kinds: bold and shy, MS007.001.004.00596; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 049. Collected as "Nineteen Sonnets by John Holmes". Revision in 7:082 titled " People at Parties". Published in Fair warning, p. 41 revision in 6:097 and duplicate in 10:034, p. 132
  - The voice, MS007.001.004.00597; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 057.
  - Hold it up to the light, 1944; MS007.001.004.00598; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 058. Published in Map of my country, p. 73; This Is My America: Poems from the Washington Post (Washington, D.C.: Washington Post, 1946) p. 167; Stained Glass, 39:20, Spring 1944.
  - Words of my own, 1954; MS007.001.004.00599; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 060. Printed on Christmas card for 1954. revisions in 10:010, p. 5 and 10:034, p. 1
  - Dialogue alone [Even now], MS007.001.004.00600; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 061. Revision located 8:060: January 14, 1935 and entitled "Even now". Published in Address to the living, p. 91; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1937, (New York: Paebar, 1938), p. 76; American Mercury, 40:96, January 1937. revisions in 8:060 and 10:010, p. 85
  - A cure of guilt, MS007.001.004.00601; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 062. Published in Saturday Review, 42:50, August 1, 1959; New York Herald-Tribune, August 30 1959. revision in 10:037, p. 141
  - The core [One sound], MS007.001.004.00602; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 063. Annotated. Revision in 9:068 is titled: One sound. Published in The double root, p. 13; Mid-Century American Poets (New York: Twayne, 1950) p. 223; Yale Review n s, 37:409-10, March 1948. revisions in 9:068 and 10:033, p. 47A
  - Country senses, 1947; MS007.001.004.00603; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 064. Annotated: "Vermont" Published in New York Herald-Tribune, September 11, 1954. duplicate in 10:035, p. 21 and revision in 10:036, p. 32
  - Chair in the field, MS007.001.004.00604; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 065. Annotated Published in The double root, p. 21; Atlantic, 180:104, August 1947. revision in 10:033, p. 32
  - The broken one, 1949-09-01; MS007.001.004.00605; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 074. Published in The double root, p. 58; Mid-Century American Poets (New York: Twayne, 1950) p. 213 sound recording in 64:001
  - Between thousand and thousands, MS007.001.004.00606; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 076. Published in Poetry, 101:265-71, January 1963. duplicate in 10:037, p. 188
  - Few in a million, MS007.001.004.00607; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 085. Published in Hopkins Review, 3:27, Winter 1950. revision in 4:86
  - The fiery element, MS007.001.004.00608; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 089. Revision in 10:010, p. 151 is annotated. Set to music as hymn of same name in Hymns for the Celebration of Life, Boston: Beacon Press, 1964. Published in Map of my country, p. 37; Saturday Review of Literature, 21:4, January 13, 1940. revisions in 7:008; 10:010, p. 151; 11:002, p. 39
  - The flower, MS007.001.004.00609; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 090.
  - The folding key, 1957-02-22; MS007.001.004.00610; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 091. Published in A Friendly Visit: Poems for Robert Frost (s l: Beloit Poetry Journal - Chapbook Number five, n d) p. 22; Beloit Poetry Journal Chapbook, 5:22, 1957. duplicates in 4:091 and 10:037, p. 109
  - For sports section of Jumbo Book, MS007.001.004.00611; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 096. Revision in 10:037, p. 100 is annotated. Revision in 10:037, p. 100 is titled: "Sports section" Collection of "Seven poems, 1957 Tufts Jumbo Book" revision in 10:037, p. 100
  - The fortune teller, 1957-02-21; MS007.001.004.00612; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 097. Published in The fortune teller, p. 3; New Poems of American Poets, No. 2 Edited by Rolfe Humphries (New York: Ballantine, 1957) p. 75. revisions in 4:98; 7:013; 10:037, p. 108; 11:003, p. 1, sound recordings in 62:001 and 67:001
  - From Brooklyn, MS007.001.004.00613; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 099. Annotated Published in The double root, p. 70; Kenyon Review, 11:114-15, Winter 1949. sound recording in 64:001
  - Guard of honor, 1950-08-01; MS007.001.004.00614; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 106. Revision in 4:107 dated Nov. 6, 1953 Published in Unitarian Register, 138:11, October 1959. revisions in 4:107; 10:035, p. 6; 10:037, p. 2
  - Hamlet with a license, MS007.001.004.00615; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 108. Revision in 4:109 is annotated. Published in Poetry Northwest, 1:4, Spring - Summer 1960. Slightly different version added in June 2009. revisions in 4:109; 10:016; 10:037, p. 124
  - Hearing Margaret, aged four, 1960; MS007.001.004.00616; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 111. Revision in 10:037, p. 133 is annotated. Published in The fortune teller, p. 71; Poetry, 95:280, February 1960. revisions in 10:037, p. 133 and 11:003, p. 60, sound recording in 66:001
  - Her walking, MS007.001.004.00617; Holmes, John (Box 4)
    Box 4 folder 113. Includes annotated copy inscribed to Doris Holmes from John Holmes. Published in Approach, 40:2, Summer 1961. revisions in 4:114; 6:028; and 10:037, p. 145